Ahmed Khaled A. Awwad

SOC Analyst Tier 1

Ahmed Awwad +201117753991 a.k.awad97@gmail.com Military service: Perfomed

Electronics and Communication Engineer, Jr SOC analyst 1 year experienced in analysis and cooperate in incident investigations. seeking to leverage my skills in a challenging SOC Analyst Tier 1 role. Committed to enhancing security operations by utilizing advanced threat detection techniques, incident response strategies. Self-learner, Self-motivated and pursued my goals to build oriented career.

ACHIEVEMENTS

CTFs writeups, Awwad's Blog ☑

Cybertalents,

Top 200 in Egypt rank. ☑

Foundations of Operation MITRE

ATT&CK, ATTACKIQ Academy 🖸

Cisco CCNAv7 🛮

Introduction to Networks Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials

Enterprise Networking, Security, and Automation

SKILLS

SIEM Solutions | EDR | SOAR

Incidents Investigation

Infrastructure & System Security

Application & Network Security

Linux | Cryptography | R&D

Network & Systems administration

Programming

Python ,Bash, C++..

Technical Reporting/Writing

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Mother tongue

English

B2- Upper Intermediate

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Communication and Electronics Engineering,

Faculty of Engineering Helwan University

Project: Email Anti-spammer system 🛮

Degree: **Excellent**

EXPERIENCE

Armed Forces

Kaspersky Administrator

Jul 2023 | Confidential

Serving as Kaspersky administrator. Monitor, Maintain and develop Kaspersky server and managed devices. Ensuring robust protection against malware and cyber threats.

Network and System Administrator

Jul 2023 | Confidential

Serving as a Network and computer systems administrator. Manage all military internal networks, systems, install, configure, and maintain organizations' computers.

Optima Professional Services (OPS)

SOC Analyst

Jul 2023 - 2024 | Part time

SOC Analyst | Tier 1

Oct 2022 – May 2023 | Full time

Monitor and analyze incidents. Analyzing Business environment and traffic baseline to enhance SOAR playbooks to reduce False-

Positive repeated incident rate. Also help reduced incident response time through efficient monitoring and analysis.

Follow-up with the IT Teams and other Business Units to develop action plans to mitigate identified vulnerabilities.

Excel Codes, Back-end Developer intern ☑

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

"ICenna " Website and Mobile Application Back-End Developer for Python (Django) for websites and applications.

Freelancer, Curriculum writer

Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Physics & Mathematics content writer, booklets content designing and translating Arabic content to English

PROJECTS

Spamurai, *Graduation project*

Spamurai is Email Anti-spammer system in cyber security field. It is Research and development (R&D) project aim to find and implement a solution to detect and prevent or lessen the interaction of users with any adware, harmful/spam emails based on content analysis as URL, TEXT and Files.

Auxilio Robotic, IEEE RAS, Certificate

IEEE Helwan Student Chapter

I was assigned to lead control team & code via Arduino.

Our objective is to structure Line follower Robot help disabled people by carrying different objects with controllable arm and following the line path to a certain destination automatically or manually through an application to control direction and movement.

COURSES & INTERNSHIPS

CCNAv7, National Telecommunication Institute (NTI)

Oct 2022 – Dec 2022

Network fundamentals, network access, IP connectivity & services, Network security fundamentals, and laying the foundation for network automation and programmability.

Certificates

Cyber Security Engineer, *Udacity*

Jul 2022 - Nov 2022

Nanodegree Expert level program by egFWD ITIDA ☑.

- Security Engineering Fundamentals
- System Security
- Infrastructure Security
- Application Security

Nanodegree Certificate 🛮

Cyber Security Engineer Intern, *VTF* □

May 2022 – Jul 2022 | Online

Cyber Security Teams and their roles. Gained knowledge in Splunk, Mitre Att&ck, OSINT, Pfsense, Cloud and Presenting skills.

Certificate 🗷

Pentester trainee, Trend Micro & CyberTalents

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Penetration Testing cycle and phases. Dived deep into OWASP top 10 vulnerabilities.

Achieved top 10 in the evaluation CTF.

Certificate 🗷

Full Stack Web Developer, Udacity

Feb 2018 - May 2018 | Online

"One Million Arab Coder" in Full-Stack Web Developer.

- Python Language
- Version control: Git GitHub

Certificate 🗷

Front-End Web Developer, Udacity

Nov 2017 - Feb 2018 | Online

"Google Developer Challenge" in Front-End Web.